Executive Summary

Efficient, reliable and highly motivated Application Solution design and Delivery professional with experience in Virtual Banking and Finance Software Solution design, Backend application development, integration and implementation. Proficiency in Master Card, VISA, JETCO, Union Pay International Integration and Certification. Experience new age technologies – QR Cash, Mobile Wallet (Apple pay), Java Spring boot, AMQ, REST API, Apache Kafka, Angular and C++.

Hong Kong

panigrahyr8@gmail.com

India Cell - +91-85990 44058

Hong Kong - +852 91700192

LinkedIn -

https://www.linkedin.com/in/r-prasad-panigrahy-a5316a147/

EXPERIENCE

Standard Chartered Bank, Hong Kong — Technology Delivery Lead

Jan 2011 - PRESENT

Roles and responsibility is to design and implement software application services for Digital Banking and Finance domain, interaction with Business, Vendor and Backend team for the project delivery.

Orange Business Services (France Telecom Group), Mumbai — *Manager* - *Engineering Services*

August 2000 - December 2010

Roles and responsibility was to design and develop voice application services using C++, VXML , SQL, Java and .NET Technologies.

SKILLS

REST API Design Java Spring Boot and Django REST Framework

Web Framework - Python Django

Fullstack application design using Angular with Node.js

AWS Cloud based Solution Design

Application design and development using C++.

KEY CONTRIBUTIONS

- Solution design and implementation for Apple Pay enablement for SCB Union Pay International Debit cards for card less transactions.
- Solution design for QR Code based ATM Cash Withdrawal
- JETCO Issuing Host Certification completion
- JETCO Chip Card Profile Certification
- 3D Secure Application Implementation for OTP SMS
- Solution design for setting up new ATM, CDM, CQM
 Infrastructure and application service ATM Front End

AWARDS

Best Solution Design for Integrating Payment Switch Application with Fraud Management System.

1 Technology Collaboration Champion 2013 award from Standard Chartered Bank Applications, Middleware API Services, Security services (Hard Disk Encryption, Software Whitelisting, Software Distribution)

PROJECTS

JETCO Integration and Certification for Virtual Bank:

This project is to implement Card Processing System (ATM Switch) to process the ATM and eCommerce Transactions of Virtual Bank customers. The scope of the project includes the following:

 Development of application modules in Card Processing System (ATM Switch) for JETCO and eCommerce, Transaction Processing.

2. Integrating Card Processing System with JETCO & Master Card.

3. Integrating Card Processing System with Virtual Bank through RESTful API.

4. Chip Card Certification (profile) for Master Card and JETCO.

Enabling 3D Secure for additional security (OTP) using VISA Application Services.

Payment Application Services Framework: —

This project is to introduce a new set of application services on the self-service terminals (ATM, Cash Deposit Machines, Cheque Deposit machines) along with the necessary backend application services.

Technology: - Java Script, C#, Oracle PL/SQL

Role: - Solution Architect and project delivery

Enhanced Security Control: —

This project is to design an implement the secured and monitoring application services to ensure the protection of the self-service terminals from unauthorized access and smooth functioning.

Role: - Solution Architect

Apple pay Mobile Wallet: —

This project is to allow bank customers to register their Debit cards in apple pay for card less transaction by using Apple Pay Mobile Wallet. This project delivered the following applications:

• Card Provisioning Web Service Interface.

Web based Card Life Cycle Management Interface

Role: - Project Delivery

Passion for Action at OBS in 2004

Employee of the Quarter at OBS in 2005

Best Customer Support at OBS in 2006

Best performance in CTI (from Nortel) in 2007

Orange Flare of the Quarter in Oct 2009

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Cantonese (under learning stage) and Odia

Fraud Management System Interface: —

This project is to setting up a Fraud prevention mechanism through technology

enablement. Aim is to integrate the ATM Switches of all countries to the Fraud

 ${\bf Manage ment\ System\ through\ a\ centralized\ Fraud\ Trap\ Interface\ component\ and\ }$

TCP/IP based middleware. Based on the scoring ATM Switch can either allow or

reject the ATM transaction.

Technology:-C++

Role: - Solution Architect

Ghana Data Centre Movement to UK (Ghana, UK): —

The project is to de-commission the ATM solution components in Ghana Data centre and setup the new ATM components in UK data centre to serve 5 African

countries. It includes:

Setting up ATM Switch Servers

VISA Integration and certifications

Other external interfaces (GHIPSS. VPAY and NCS) integration

• Core banking and other backend integration

Regional Contact Centre - Singapore, Hong Kong, China and Malaysia

Description – This project is to design, develop and implement the IVR and other

contact centre applications for Standard Chartered Bank.

Technology - Genesys Voice Platform, VXML, SQL, Java, Web Services

Roles and responsibilities -

• Technology Project Management

Vendor management (for requirement understanding, scope of work,

system design, development and implementation)

Backend (core banking, credit card system) and testing team

engagement

Project activities tracking, escalations and monitoring

EDUCATION

Datapro, Sunabeda, Odisha — MDCS

June 1996 - December 1998

Complete Master Diploma in Computer Science course that includes C++,

Oracle, Unix and RDBMS Programming - SQL, PL/SQL.

Khallikote College, Berhampur, Odisha — B.A. (Hon's)

April 1994 - May 1996

Completed Bachelor in Arts with Education Honors and English Literature.